☑ danqingw@andrew.cmu.edu
☐ dqwang122.github.io
☑ dqwang122

Danqing Wang

Research Interest: Interested in various generation tasks, including large language models and biological sequences. Devoted to helping the machine generate new content that benefits human life. Mainly focus on (but not limited to):

- o Reasoning and Planning in Large Language Models: Multi-agent Collaboration, Alignment, etc.
- o Al for Science: Peptide Design, Antibody Discovery, etc.

Github: https://github.com/dqwang122 **Scholar**: Google Scholar, Semantic Scholar

		Language Control of the Control		
— /	dı.	ıca	+1	α n
	ш	и.а	ш	CHI

	Education
2024 – Current	PhD in Language Technologies Institute , <i>Carnegie Mellon University</i> Advisor: Prof. Lei Li
2022 – 2023	PhD in Computer Science , <i>UC, Santa Barbara</i> Advisor: Prof. Lei Li
2018 – 2021	Master in Computer Science, Fudan University Advisor: Prof. Xipeng Qiu and Prof. Xuanjing Huang
2014 – 2018	Bachelor in Computer Science and Technology , Fudan University Ranking: Top 10%
	Experience

Experience

2023.6 – 2024.1	Research Scientist Intern, Meta AI (FAIR)
	Advisor: Yuandong Tian
2020.4 - 2022.8	Research Scientist, ByteDance Research (Al Lab)

Advisor: Jiaze Chen, Hao Zhou, and Lei Li

Main Publications

Large Language Models

Under	Cooperative Strategic Planning Enhances Reasoning Capabilities in Large Language Models
Submission	Danqing Wang, Zhuorui Ye, Fei Fang, Lei Li

Under **ThinkHub: Enhancing Large Language Models with Implicit Policy and Explicit Knowledge** Submission Danqing Wang, JianXin Ma, Lei Li

Preprint on arXiv Learning Personalized Alignment for Evaluating Open-ended Text Generation Some Danqing Wang, Kevin Yang, Hanlin Zhu, Xiaomeng Yang, Andrew Cohen, Lei Li, Yuandong Tian

EMNLP 2023 Learning from Mistakes via Cooperative Study Assistant for Large Language Models & Danqing Wang, Lei Li

EMNLP 2023 Instructscore: Towards Explainable Text Generation Evaluation with Automatic Feedback & Wenda Xu, Danqing Wang, Liangming Pan, Zhenqiao Song, Markus Freitag, William Yang Wang, Lei Li

NeurIPS 2023 ALGO: Synthesizing Algorithmic Programs with Generated Oracle Verifiers & Kexun Zhang, Danqing Wang, Jingtao Xia, William Yang Wang, Lei Li

Al for Science

KDD 2024 Global Human-guided Counterfactual Explanations for Molecular Properties via Reinforcement Learning %

Danqing Wang*, Antonis Antoniades*, Kha-Dinh Luong, Edwin Zhang, Mert Kosan, Jiachen Li, William Yang Wang, Ambuj Singh, Lei Li

ICLR 2023 On Pre-training Language Model for Antibody & Danqing Wang, Fei Ye, Hao Zhou

KDD 2023 Accelerating Antimicrobial Peptide Discovery with Latent Structure & Danqing Wang, Zeyu Wen, Fei Ye, Lei Li, Hao Zhou

Text Summarization

- ACL 2021 Contrastive Aligned Joint Learning for Multilingual Summarization %
 - Finding Danqing Wang, Jiaze Chen, Hao Zhou, Xipeng Qiu, Lei Li
- ACL 2020 Heterogeneous Graph Neural Networks for Extractive Document Summarization & Danqing Wang*, Pengfei Liu*, Yining Zheng, Xipeng Qiu and Xuanjing Huang
- ACL 2020 Extractive Summarization as Text Matching & Ming Zhong*, Pengfei Liu*, Yiran Chen, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu and Xuanjing Huang
- ACL 2019 Searching for Effective Neural Extractive Summarization: What Works and What's Next & Ming Zhong*, Pengfei Liu*, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu, Xuanjing Huang

Academic Services

- o Program Committee of ICML, ICLR, NeurIPS, ACL, EMNLP, AAAI
- o TA for CS190I Deep Learning (Winter 2023) and CS165B Machine Learning (Spring 2023)
- Local Organization Chair of Socal NLP Symposium 2022

Honor

- 2022 Academic Excellence Fellowship
- 2021 Shanghai Outstanding Graduates (5% of graduates)
- 2020 Venustech Scholarship (1% of Fudan students)
- 2019 Scholarship for Outstanding Students (First Prize)
- 2017 Fudan's Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program

Bibliography

- [1] Chenxin An, Ming Zhong, Yiran Chen, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuanjing Huang. Enhancing scientific papers summarization with citation graph. In *Proceedings of the AAAI conference on artificial intelligence*, volume 35, pages 12498–12506, 2021.
- [2] Yiran Chen, Pengfei Liu, Ming Zhong, Zi-Yi Dou, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuan-Jing Huang. Cdevalsumm: An empirical study of cross-dataset evaluation for neural summarization systems. In Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2020, pages 3679–3691, 2020.
- [3] Yiran Chen, Zhenqiao Song, Xianze Wu, Danqing Wang, Jingjing Xu, Jiaze Chen, Hao Zhou, and Lei Li. Mtg: A benchmark suite for multilingual text generation. In *Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: NAACL 2022*, pages 2508–2527, 2022.
- [4] Danqing Wang, Antonis Antoniades, Kha-Dinh Luong, Edwin Zhang, Mert Kosan, Jiachen Li, Ambuj Singh, William Yang Wang, and Lei Li. Global human-guided counterfactual explanations for molecular properties via reinforcement learning. In *Proceedings of the 30th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining*, KDD '24, page 2991–3000, New York, NY, USA, 2024. Association for Computing Machinery.
- [5] Danqing Wang, Jiaze Chen, Xianze Wu, Hao Zhou, and Lei Li. Cnewsum: a large-scale summarization dataset with human-annotated adequacy and deducibility level. In *Natural Language Processing and Chinese Computing: 10th CCF International Conference, NLPCC 2021, Qingdao, China, October 13–17, 2021, Proceedings, Part I 10*, pages 389–400. Springer, 2021.
- [6] Danqing Wang, Jiaze Chen, Hao Zhou, Xipeng Qiu, and Lei Li. Contrastive aligned joint learning for multilingual summarization. In *Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL-IJCNLP* 2021, pages 2739–2750, 2021.
- [7] Danqing Wang and Lei Li. Learn from mistakes through cooperative interaction with study assistant. The 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) 2023, 2023.
- [8] Danqing Wang, Pengfei Liu, Yining Zheng, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuan-Jing Huang. Heterogeneous graph neural networks for extractive document summarization. In *Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics*, pages 6209–6219, 2020.

- [9] Danqing Wang, Pengfei Liu, Ming Zhong, Jie Fu, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuanjing Huang. Exploring domain shift in extractive text summarization. *arXiv preprint arXiv:1908.11664*, 2019.
- [10] Danqing Wang, Zeyu Wen, Fei Ye, Lei Li, and Hao Zhou. Accelerating antimicrobial peptide discovery with latent structure. In *Proceedings of the 29th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery* and Data Mining, KDD '23, page 2243–2255, New York, NY, USA, 2023. Association for Computing Machinery.
- [11] Danqing Wang, Kevin Yang, Hanlin Zhu, Xiaomeng Yang, Andrew Cohen, Lei Li, and Yuandong Tian. Learning personalized story evaluation. *arXiv preprint arXiv:2310.03304*, 2023.
- [12] Danqing Wang, Fei YE, and Hao Zhou. On pre-training language model for antibody. In *The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations*, 2023.
- [13] Wenda Xu, Danqing Wang, Liangming Pan, Zhenqiao Song, Markus Freitag, William Wang, and Lei Li. INSTRUCTSCORE: Towards explainable text generation evaluation with automatic feedback. In Houda Bouamor, Juan Pino, and Kalika Bali, editors, *Proceedings of the 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*, pages 5967–5994, Singapore, December 2023. Association for Computational Linguistics.
- [14] Kexun Zhang, Danqing Wang, Jingtao Xia, William Yang Wang, and Lei Li. Algo: synthesizing algorithmic programs with Ilm-generated oracle verifiers. In *Proceedings of the 37th International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems*, pages 54769–54784, 2023.
- [15] Ming Zhong, Pengfei Liu, Yiran Chen, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuan-Jing Huang. Extractive summarization as text matching. In *Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics*, pages 6197–6208, 2020.
- [16] Ming Zhong, Pengfei Liu, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuan-Jing Huang. Searching for effective neural extractive summarization: What works and what's next. In *Proceedings of the 57th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics*, pages 1049–1058, 2019.
- [17] Ming Zhong, Danqing Wang, Pengfei Liu, Xipeng Qiu, and Xuan-Jing Huang. A closer look at data bias in neural extractive summarization models. In *Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on New Frontiers in Summarization*, pages 80–89, 2019.